# Steven Basart

Computer Science PhD student

xksteven.com xksteven at uchicago.edu (954) 805-3651

### Research Interests

My primary area of focus has been within computer vision. For the years of 2015-2017, I have worked on generative models, specifically GANs, coming up with both a measure and a method to use GANs to interpret other classifiers. I have since begun exploring techniques to make models more robust. The majority of my research focuses on applications of machine learning.

### Education

Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science) 2014 to ongoing

University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois

Bachelor of Science (Biochemistry and Computer Science) 2010 to 2014

University of Miami, Miami, Florida

### Courses

Machine Learning Robot Planning/Al Computer Vision

Algorithms Databases

# Teaching

TA for Machine Learning (Autumn TA for Intro. to Computer Science TA for Machine Learning(Spring 2017) (Autumn 2016) 2016)

TA for Intro. to Computer Science TA for Computational Biology (Winter 2016) (Autumn 2015)

# Research Experience

#### **Computer Science 2014 to current**

I am working with Dr. Greg Shakhnarovich at TTIC in the areas of machine learning and computer vision.

#### Biochemistry 2011 to 2014

I worked with Dr. Richard Myers at the University of Miami trying to create a generic genetic therapy via transducible gene editing proteins. I ran western blots, gel electrophoresis, transductions, PCR, and electroporation

### Technical

Python C Java

Pytorch/Tensorflow Git / SVN

# Experience

#### Google Brain Research Intern Summer 2018

I worked in NLP and collaborated with several teams. I worked in the area of Fact Checking related to this paper to deal with the problem of content abuse and also worked with the Google News team. **python**, **pytorch**, **tensorflow**, **apache-beam**, **flume** 

#### Here Maps Research Intern Summer 2017

I worked on models to better predict arrival times (ETA estimates) and lane level navigation prediction which can be used for autonomous vehicles. **python**, **pytorch** 

#### Here Maps Research Intern Summer 2016

I developed a model that creates road probability maps that can be used to detect differences between artificial maps and the real roads. **python, tensorflow** 

# **Projects**

#### **OpenGL Renderer**

#### myRenderer

I created a simple OpenGL renderer to render some height maps and draw some objects. Applies simple lighting and texturing.

#### BattleShip game over internet

#### BattleShip

I created a simple Battleship game in C that has a client, server interface.

# **Publications**

#### **Natural Adversarial Examples ICML 2019 Workshop**

In this work we constructed a dataset which captures long tail distributions to highlight where current model: fail in terms of generalization.

#### **Analysis of Generative Adeversarial Models 2017**

This is my master's work in which I introduce a novel measure for quantitatively assessing the quality of generative models and present a method for utilizing GANs to interpret classifiers.